# **Aubrey Camille Soliman**

I am a PHP programmer with 3+ years of commercial experience. I have spear-headed multiple related project feature release. I like to read about the latest technologies and current popular frameworks during my spare time. Currently I am learning AngularJS, C#, ASP .NET, Visual Basic and SQL Management Studio.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Mapua University (Philippines)

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology. Major in SAS Business Analytics.

# TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

#### **WEB TECHNOLOGIES**

PHP, Linux, Apache, JSON/API, Bootstrap, HTML5/JavaScript/CSS, ASP.NET MVC, AngularJS

#### **DATABASES**

MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server

#### **TOOLS/LIBRARIES**

PHP Storm, Git, Redmine, Backlog, Ganglia, ReShaper, Visual Studio 2012

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### MVP Studio (New Zealand)

## Software Development Intern

Oct 2017 - Present

Currently working on the on-boarding task.

ASP .NET MVC, C#, AngularJS, HTML/JavaScript/AJAX/CSS/jQuery and SQL Server

#### ImpactNPO (New Zealand)

# Website Developer (Volunteer)

Sep 2017 (2-Day Event)

Website development made during hackathon event led by ImpactNPO for client She# (https://www.shesharp.co.nz/).

I have created two of the pages (About Our Team and Event) using Wordpress.

#### Aiming Global Services Inc. (Philippines)

#### Development Staff

Mar 2017 – Apr 2017

Project: Eagle Fantasy Golf

Software Engineer

Localization of language from Chinese to English using Unity 3D

#### KLab Cyscorpions (Philippines)

Oct 2013 - Feb 2017

Projects: Eternal Uprising and Lord of the Dragons

- PHP (CakePHP Framework), MySQL, Linux, Apache, MVC, HTML/JavaScript /CSS(Bootstrap/
- Developed feature releases with MVC design pattern using DietCake Framework (optimized CakePHP framework)
- Main Developer in multiple API release and continuous CMS update

- User data management (migration, maintenance, data update and backup)
- Creation of API, Database Schema Design and Logic Specifications
- Development environment (LOCAL → STAGING → PRODUCTION)
- Redmine Issue Management (Test if bug is occurring → assign it to developers or fix it myself → re-test if bug is still occurring)
- Investigation of issues sent by a player and customer support via email
- Monitoring of Amazon Web Services (AWS) instance using Ganglia

## **INTERESTS**

- Trying out other PHP frameworks such as Laravel and Silverstripe.
- A very active person who loves trying out new things and is always up for any challenge.
- Loves travelling a lot, learning other cultures, tasting different kind of foods and taking photographs.

## REFEREES

Available on request